# **CURRICULUM VITAE**



7B, Trung My Tay 10 Street, District 12 Ho Chi Minh City, VIETNAM

(+84)90 749 0959

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/hoang-nguyen/50/844/a24 18/01/1985

#### Looking for a Data Scientist position in Ho Chi Minh City

#### Summary

I received a master's degree in Computer Science at John Von Neumann institute - VNUHCMC. With my knowlegde in Business, Finance, Mathematics, Information Technology and five years experience in Data Science; I am a good fit in Data Scientist position.

#### Education

2011-2013 John von Neumann Institute (Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City)

Master's degree of Computer Science (language of studying in English). GPA: 7.73/10 (Top 5 graduation GPA).

2003-2008 Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology,

Engineering degree in Telecommunication (2008). GPA: 6.99/10

## Professional experiences

08/2015 - present

Mobivi Coporation – Data Scientist – BI team leader

- Do reporting, planning, forecasting data for business, finance, collection, supply chain.

- Providing business insights related to customers understanding, scoring of various metrics (top performance customer, top products, top salesman, ...)

TMA Solution company – TMA R&D Department – Sr. Data Analyst

03/2014 - 08/2015

- NLP project - build a system can classify text data from the internet is negative/positive about the product.

- Business Intelligent project – build a system can make report, dashboard, model for evaluating performance and quality of other projects in TMA

04/2013-07/2013

Internship at PBN Consulting Company – Data Mining project

06/2009 - 11/2011 06/2008 - 06/2009 VTC Digicom company - Network Engineer – IPTV project CMC Telecom Company - Telecommunication Engineer - Call Center Project

## Skills and qualifications

#### Data Science

Analysis

SVM, k-NN, Regression, Classification, Clustering **Platform** Pentaho BI System, Microsoft BI System

Data Warehousing,

DataBase MSSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Redshift **BigData** Hadoop, Hive, Hortonworks, Spark

Computer skills

Statistics and Computing: R, Python, Excel VBA Office Microsoft Office (Specific Excel) Programming

Java, Scala, SQL, Javascript, HTML

Languages

Native language Vietnamese Professional working proficiency English

## Honors

- Received scholarship up to the totality of the tuition fees (\$18000) to study master program at John Von Neumann -VNU HCMC (2011 - 2013).

Open Office

- Second prize useful application competition 5th– Electric Electronic department, 10/2007.
- Encourage scholarship of HCM city university of technique in 2005 2006
- Certificate of merit of Student Society HCM city and Headmaster of HCM city University of Technology for the excellent leader of union branch (2006).

## Hobbies and interests

Social Activities Activities

Sports game, football, badminton, billiard

# Reference

Dr. Nguyễn Quang-Lecturer of JVN Institute

Mobile: 091 568 4235

Email: quang.nguyen@jvn.edu.vn